NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files. 6174/016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Board of Directors Reception Dinner and Meeting December 9-10, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Tentative meeting agenda; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors from president Dick Ianuzzi re constitution update to accommodate unification with NEA, November 4, 2005; redline edits to constitution; memo with text of Randi Weingarten statement re UFT contract ratification, November 7, 2005; memo to local president from Ianuzzi re training available for public relations campaigns to support school budgets, November 2; NYSUT Solidarity Fund application form; evaluation form for NYSUT Board of Directors retreat of September 16-18, 2005; report of executive vice president Alan Lubin re election results and plans for 2006, November 29; report of second vice president Kathleen Donahue; Report of NYSUT Task Force on Retiree Services, 2002; report of secretary-treasurer Ivan Tiger; NYSUT balance sheet as of August 31, 2005; NYSUT membership comparison as of October 31, 2005, vs fiscal year end 2005 (August 31, 2005); consolidated financial statements for years ended August 31, 2005 and 2004; NYSUT Benefit Trust Summary of Material Modifications and Notice to Participants, May 2005; related financial documents; social services report; field and legal report; organizing report
- Board of Directors Retreat Planning Committee 7/12/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  List of retreat committee members; memo re planning committee meeting
- Board of Directors Meeting 6/27/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Memo; outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira
- Board of Directors New Board Orientation 5/23/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Program; report of first vice president Maria Neira; list of attendees; list of Board of Regents, with summary of powers and duties; NYSUT booklet, Education and Learning Trust: Your Professional Development Source: Summer 2005 Course Catalog; NYSUT booklet, School Related Professionals: Professional Development Program; NYSUT Briefing Bulletin, May 2005, "83.5% of School Budgets Passed," with list of school districts whose budgets were defeated; NYSUT Information Bulletin re role of the mentor in district-based mentoring programs
- Board of Directors Meeting January 28-29, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; dues proposal; handwritten notes
- Board of Directors Officers and Associates Meeting 1/25/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Agenda; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of January 28; agenda for Board of Directors' meeting of January 28-29; notes from Officers' meeting of January 4, 2005; list of management/confidential salary adjustments for FY 2004/2005, per May 11, 2004, Officers' meeting; working 2004-05 salary schedule; 2005 Constituency Awards nominees; balance sheet for Retiree Funds for fiscal years ended 8/31/01 8/31/04; organizing flyers for Associate Member for Higher Education program; memo from NYSUT Office of Special Counsel re draft revised NYSUT policy prohibiting sexual harassment, January 25; benefit plan comparison chart; revised dues and revenue projection; 2005 constitutional changes, with marked-up copy; proposed 2005 Representative Assembly Resolutions Committee chairs and vice chairs; memo re upcoming AFT conferences re SRP (School Related Professionals), special conference re civil human rights, women's rights, higher education, January 25. See also Officers' and Associates meetings
- Board of Directors Meeting December 10-11, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Memo re tentative meeting agenda; minutes of Board of Directors meetings of September 10-11, 2004, and October 31, 2004; president's report; report of first vice president Richard Ianuzzi; report of executive director, Field & Legal Services; list of requests for affiliation; post-election summary from executive vice president Alan Lubin; newsletter of New York State Labor-Religion Coalition re sweatshops; report, Future of NYSUT's Retiree Program; NYSUT Managerial Positions, for approval by NYSUT Executive Committee and Board of Directors, December 10-11, 2004; NYSUT Building Corporation membership meeting agenda, December 11, 2004; document, Implementation of Actions by the 2004 Representative Assembly, March 25-27, 2004; 2005 Representative Assembly action items for Board approval; spring 2005 course catalog, Education and Learning Trust; disks marked BOD Power Point
- Board of Directors Retreat October 28-31, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Memo re plans for retreat; proposed schedule (agenda); list of social/recreational events; evaluation summary of Board of Directors' retreat, November 11; summary reports of items discussed; materials re Regents middle-level policy
- Board of Directors Meeting September 10-11, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Agenda; agenda for Executive Committee meeting; president's report; vice president's report; report of first vice president Toni Cortese; report of executive director, Field & Legal Services; report of the secretary-treasurer; report of the Task Force on Small and Rural Locals: One Tree Many Branches; requests for affiliation; legislative update; State Education Department Resolution in Recognition of Distinguished Service for Toni Cortese; journal, International Project of the New York State Labor-Religion Coalition; minutes of Board of Directors meeting of August 4, 2004
- Board of Directors Meeting 8/4/04, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Agenda; minutes of June 28, 2004, meeting; materials re 2004 Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; list of members of Political Action Committee; conference agenda; glossy printed flyers by NYSUT re Democratic presidential candidate John Kerry on mandatory overtime, access to higher education
- Board of Directors Meeting January 23-24, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  Outline of report of first vice president; Regents' Report Card; memo re expiration of the term of office of members of the Board of Regents, January 7, 2004; handwritten notes
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 05/16/06, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 4/4/06, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 12/13/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  Agenda; county by county impact of alternative state aid scenarios for 2006-07
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 11/15/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  Agenda; list of meeting dates
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 5/24/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- BOCES District Superintendent Committee 11/16/04, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- BOCES Leadership Conference September 29-October 1, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  Printed program for 34th annual conference; related materials
- BOCES Leadership Conference 10/21/05, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  Registration materials; request for speaker
- BOCES Conference October 22-23, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  BOCES issues/comments
- BOCES Lobby Day 2004-2005 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  Brief memos
- BOCES Merger Studies, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  Correspondence re possible merger of Monroe 1 BOCES with Monroe 2 BOCES, August
- Buchbinder Tunick & Co see Zimmerman
- Budget NYSUT Proposed Budget, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Executive Committee presentation of draft NYSUT 2005-06 Budget, with cover letter from secretary-treasurer Ivan Tiger, June 2, 2005
- Budget Management Planning Committee 5/11/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Memo to NYSUT officers and associates re management/confidential compensation analysis, May 16, 2005; confidential Dick Ianuzzi's Officers' Retreat notes, April 26-27, 2005; outline of officers' meeting, May 3, 2005; program of the 2005 NYSUT Leadership Institute at Cornell University, August 5; 2005 committee nominations; testimony of Antonia Cortese, First Vice President, New York State United Teachers to the Senate and Assembly Standing Committees on Education on the Regents Learning Standards and High School Graduation Requirements, October 22, 2003
- Budget State Budget, 2004-2005 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  2005-06 Budget Analysis: Review of Enacted Budget, from the Office of the State Comptroller, Alan G. Hevesi, May 17, 2005; review of the 2004-05 Legislative Budget Agreement, New York State Division the Budget, George E. Pataki, Governor, August 20, 2004; memo from AFT legislative associate re passage of 2006 congressional budget, noting tax cuts and cuts to education, Medicaid, job training, and other domestic programs, failure of several AFT-supported amendments, links to individual legislators' votes, April 29, 2005
- Business Council of New York State, Inc. Education and Business Expo, 1989-2004 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Printed brochure, "Engage New York: A Call to Engage Business in Promoting Education Excellence," by the Business Council; charts correlating reading scores, 4th grade English Language Arts, and funding; program for event at Southern Saratoga County Chamber, featuring Commissioner of Education Richard Mills; press release re Education and Business Expo for October 1, 2004; 1990 Business/Labor Education Symposium agenda; Business Council and NYS AFL-CIO working paper for symposium, "Schools for the Future"; brochure, "Viewpoints: Raising Our Sights in Education," remarks of R. Quintus Anderson, chairman, The Aarque Companies, before the NYS Board of Regents, published by Public Policy Institute, February 1990; The Anderson Committee Report: Report of the Statewide Steering Committee on Preparation for Employment and/or Postsecondary Education, by R. Quintus Anderson, chairman, submitted to the NYS Board of Regents, January 16, 1990; position paper, "What the Business Council of New York State, Inc., Thinks about Public School Choice," October 1989
- Business Council of New York State, Inc. Dan Walsh 10/19/99 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Correspondence between NYSUT president Tom Hobart and Dan Walsh, Business Council of New York State, Inc., re meeting to discuss proposal that NYSUT, AFT, and Business Council develop model for validating teaching practices, December 1996-January, 1997; related correspondence with Marge Mayo, Al Shanker; special report, "Measuring Up in Our Schools: Improving Assessment and Accountability," by the Public Policy Institute, December 1988, with cover letter from Walsh (as president of institute) to Hobart; related press release; newspaper clippings
- Business Council of New York State, Inc. Mayo 1997-1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Advance copy of Public Policy Institute report, "Separate and Unequal: The Reading Gap in New York Elementary Schools," with cover letter from the corporate secretary of the Business Council, noting that Marge (Margarita) Mayo, Business Council director of quality, education and training, had suggested sending it to NYSUT first vice president Antonia Cortese, February 18, 1998; letters from Cortese commenting on report; cover letter from Mayo to Cortese with article from The Economist, April 3, 1997; article, "Don't Read, Don't Tell: Clinton's Phony War on Illiteracy," citing high cost and high failure rate of Reading Recovery program, by Robert W. Sweet, Jr., with note from Mayo to Cortese, March 2, 1997; paper evaluating cost and effectiveness of Reading Recovery program, January 1, 1997; draft NYSUT Reading Resolution for 1998 Representative Assembly, supporting early phonics instruction, February 20, 1998; draft resolution on BOCES, February 20, 1998; handwritten notes
- Business Councils Education Task Force 1/18/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Linda Sanford (IBM executive and chair of the Business Council Education Task Force) comments to the New York State Board of Regents, 9/10/ 04; letter from Sanford to Maria Neira, requesting a meeting
- Cabinet Meeting 12/13/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  Agenda; notes from October 25 Cabinet meeting; organizational chart of NYSUT departments; list of future organizing opportunities; Bicentennial Commission Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Strategic Plan executive summary; letter to UFT president Randi Weingarten from Republican Assembly member Vincent Ignizio, soliciting support for elimination of sales tax on books ("reading tax"), November 14
- Cabinet Meeting 10/25/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  Agenda; notes from September 27 Cabinet meeting; annual report of the general counsel to the executive director and officers for the 2004-2005 administrative year; 2004-05 Organizing Report; evaluation form, NYSUT Board of Directors' Retreat, September 16-18, 2005; letter from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi to Gerald Reynolds, chair, U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, expressing deep concern over remarks Reynolds made re Albany City School District, noting diversion of millions of dollars in funds from public education by unproven charter schools, lack of federal funding for No Child Left Behind mandates, September 28; background paper, "Current Increases in Energy Costs Present a Serious Problem for School Districts Operating Under a Contingency Budget, and an Opportunity to Change the Rules," with recommended resolution urging the addition of energy costs to expenditures exempt from contingency budget spending caps
- Cabinet Meeting 9/27/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  Agenda; notes from September 13 and June 22 Cabinet meeting; organizational chart of NYSUT departments; memo re Republican Mainstream Coalition, a group of Republicans with moderate views, and its 501(c)3 not-for-profit research arm, the Center for Economic and Environmental Partnership (CEEP), recommending a $2000 contribution from NYSUT for its operating budget, September 26; materials re Higher Education Database Project; memo re retirement consultants
- Cabinet Meeting 9/13/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  Agenda; flyer, "No Child Left Behind," showing images of children from Hurricane Katrina, photos of President Bush and advisors, with timeline of White House response to event; resolutions due to expire in 2006; memo re retiree health insurance for management and confidential staff who were not grandfathered into enhanced benefits, July 21, 2005; production chart for ads and editorial support, online communications
- Cabinet Meeting 5/25/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  Agenda; notes of Officers and Associates' meeting of April 12, 2005; memo re PSC support; memo from director of human resources, recommending that mandatory post-hiring medical exams on new hires be continued despite learning of no cost savings on insurance rates, May 16, 2005
- Cambridge International Career Awards 5/1/00, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  University of Cambridge Local Examinations Syndicate Home Economic Examinations syllabus for 2001; materials re Cambridge Career Award for Information and Telecommunications Technology; Cambridge International Examinations meeting agenda, May 1, 2000
- Campaign for Youth, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  Letter to President George W. Bush ("Memo to the White House on Reconnecting Our Youth") with attached recommendations endorsed by over listed 200 organizations for disadvantaged youth, January 27, 2005
- Capital Area Labor of Love 5/23/06, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  Invitation; program for tribute dinner "honoring our government, business, labor, and community partners for their leadership, vision, commitment" to benefit the Capital Area Boys & Girls Clubs. See also Two Together
- Capital District Labor Parade Committee Tribute Reception 12/16/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  Invitation; memos
- Capital District Labor Parade 10/2/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  Memos from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to NYSUT staff re Capital District parade
- Capital District Regional Office see Regional Offices
- Celebration of Learning see Widmeyer Communications
- Charter Schools Q and A 11/22/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  Fact sheet (questions and answers) about charter schools with cover note from UFT to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, received November 22, 2004
- Charter Schools Articles, Reports, 1996-2002 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  AFT report, "Charter School Laws: Do They Measure Up?" 1996; U.S Department of Education National Study of Charter Schools, "The State of the Charter Schools: Third-Year Report," May 1999; AFT Educational Issues Policy Brief, "Charter Schools Update," June 1999; AFT Charter School Study, "Do Charter Schools Measure Up? The Charter School Experiment after Ten Years," May 14-15, 2002; downloaded articles from Education Week, Education Daily, New York Times, Albany Times-Union, other publications; Hart opinion survey of charter school teachers, 1998; NYSUT Policy on Charter Schools, approved by Board of Directors 3/12/99; Charter Schools Institute, State University of New York, press release announcing 90 applications to open new schools in 40 communities, with attached list, October 25, 1999; materials from the Michigan Prospect for Renewed Citizenship, including three papers, "Are Charter Schools Accountable?' "Evaluating Charter Schools: Questions We Should Ask and Why" and "Test Scores: Charter School Students Compared to Those in Neighborhood Public Schools"
- Charter Schools For-Profit Industry, 1999-2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Profiles of for-profit charter school companies, with cover narrative, "The Changing Face of Charter Schools: Overview of the For-Profit Charter School Industry," 1999"; materials of State Education Department Board of Regents meetings, including announcement re Status of Schools under Registration Review (SURR), January 7, 2000, amendment to Commissioner's Regulations re charter school, June 29, 1999, and approvals of charter school applications, March 15, 2001; NYSUT memo re update on charter school approvals, May 26, 2000; fiscal implications of New York charter schools
- Choice (School Choice), 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  AFT report, "Myths and Facts about Private School Choice," fall 1993, with cover memo to AFT Executive Council; AFT research report, "Public School Teachers & Their Private School Choices: Getting the Facts Straight," April 1996; draft special report by Carnegie Foundation, "School Choice," 1992; School Choice Proceedings: The Fourteenth Conference of the University/Urban Schools National Task Force, CUNY, October 29-30, 1992; correspondence re regional strategy meeting on choice, 1989; AFT legislative alert, November 21, 1991
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Meeting 12/6/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  CLUW National Officers Council meeting agenda, December 6, 2006; Labor Coalition for Community Action Mission Statement; list of duties of national CLUW officers; state assignments of CLUW National Officers Council as of December 2005; list of standing committee co-chairs; 13th biennial CLUW convention program, amended constitution, and adopted resolutions, including "The Disgrace of Hurricane Katrina," condemning federal response, calling for increase in minimum wage, "Stop Pension Piracy," re airline industry attempt to default on pension obligations, "Opposition to Roberts Nomination for Chief Justice of U.S. Supreme Court," "Wake Up Wal-Mart," "Healthcare Coverage for All," others
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Conf. Call 12/6/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Agenda; convention resolutions; event information grid
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) International Human Rights Day 12/10/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Restoring every worker's right to a Voice @ Work: Toolkit for Day of Action to Restore Workers' Freedom to Form Unions and Bargain Collectively (AFL-CIO); agenda, resolutions, and related material from CLUW National Officers Council meeting, 12/6; health-related flyers (cervical cancer screening, HIV/AIDS)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Correspondence, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  Memo from CLUW membership coordinator reminding NYSUT vice president Maria Neira that as national vice president of CLUW, she needed to renew her national CLUW membership, with attached membership application; newsletter, CLUW News (convention summary issue), July-September 2005
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 11/7/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  Meeting agenda; comments from NYSUT vice president Neira on Regents Policy Statement on Early Education for Student Achievement in a Global Community, September 29; internal NYSUT memos re algebra exam, literacy program; materials re teacher pay incentives in Denver, Colorado, public school system. See also Johanna Duncan-Poitier; see also James Kadamus
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 9/20/05 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Tentative agenda; June 2005 Regents Surveys Overview Summary re survey of teachers re their experience with the Regents exams; internal memos re exams; memo from Chuck Santelli to NYSUT officers re Education Summit 2005; description of NYSUT goals for NYS High School Reform Destination Diploma Forum of March 21-22, 2005
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 7/11/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  Agenda; materials re legal requirements for school year calendar; process for resolving local disputes; important dates for grade 3-8 tests in 2005-06
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 5/4/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  Tentative agenda; issues of concern for meeting with commissioner; review of preliminary draft middle-level regulations; examination dates for 2005-06 school year; handwritten notes
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 3/16/05, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  Tentative and revised agenda; list of members of Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 10/12/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  Memo from vice president Neira to NYSUT Board of Directors re State Education Department's latest middle-level proposal, September 24; text of SED proposal, August 26
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 5/12/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Draft letter (marked confidential) from NYS Council of School Superintendents to superintendents urging support for school finance reform, noting pending court decision in Campaign for Fiscal Equity, May 2004; handwritten notes
- Commissioner Mills Meeting 1/28/04, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  Agenda; proposed resolution by NYSUT Board of Directors re middle-level education; eligibility criteria for students with disabilities participating in the state's assessment system; spreadsheet showing umber of public and nonpublic school students with severe disabilities in various subject categories, 2002; bar graphs showing increases in student achievement since 1999
- Committee of 100 March 14-15, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  List of NYSUT officers; NYSUT flyer, There's Still a Better Choice, re implementation of Campaign for Fiscal Equity decision; fact sheets on teacher centers, health care, CUNY, SUNY, SUNY Community Colleges, UFT (NYC), K-12; tentative agenda for lobbying day
- Committee of 100 May 23-24, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  Fact sheets on retirement issues, charter schools, higher education, health care, labor, and K-12, with cover letter to the members of the NYS legislature from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin, May 24, 2005; lists of members of state Senate and Assembly, Assembly Education Committee, Senate Finance Committee, Assembly Higher Education Committee, Assembly Governmental Employees Committee; agenda for lobbying day
- Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Pre-Meeting November 28-29, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 36)